EDUCATIONAL INFO

Monterrey Institute of Technology and Higher Education. - GUADALAJARA JAL MEXICO

BACHELOR OF ANIMATION AND DIGITAL ART 2018 - 2022

On course

My career specializes in animation, videogames and visual effects.

Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (B2- CEFR)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages

- HTML/CSS/javascript
- -C# -C++

Web technologies

- -Node.js
- -MySQL
- -Express
- -React

3d softwares

- -Maya
- -Unity -Substance

Other

- -Agile metodologies (scrum)
- -Git
- -VSCode

ACHIEVEMENTS

NOT SO BEE-ZY was semifinalist in Final Frame 2021 which is a selection with the best national projects of my career

HOBBIES

I love playing videogames, reading and listening relaxing music. My favorite activity is playing american football, I love sports in which I have to do my best to reach an objective and coolaborate with other people to reach that goal.

LET'S CHAT:

+52 3334953311

Guadalajara, Mexico, Zapopan Jal. fernandohazell@gmail.com https://portfolio-fernando.herokuapp.com/ www.linkedin.com/in/ fernandohab

Fernando Ascencio

Programmer - Available starting from July 2022

PROFILE:

I like to create interactive experiences with which people can have fun and have a good time, I love to create new stories and make them land in a functional application that people can enjoy and I believe that soft skills are more important than technical knowledge to carry out a project.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full stack web developer

E-COMMERCE - DIGITAL HOUSE

MAY 2021 - OCTOBER 2021 - GUADALAJARA JAL. MEXICO

- -Web designer
 - Handling user interactions and interface animations.
 - Implement good practices in development (responsive, UX).
- -Front end developer
 - Use of Session and Cookies to store information.
 - Implementation of JavaScript validations for forms.
- -Back end developer
 - Creation and commissioning of a web server.
 - Analysis, design and implementation of a database system.
 - Authentication and management of user sessions.
 - Integration with other platforms through APIs.

Video game programmer

CRITTER THIEVES - PC VIDEO GAME FEBRUARY 2021 - JUNE 2021 - GUADALAJARA JAL. MEXICO

I was the producer and programmer of a project developed with Unity on a mouse that ventures into a mansion full of traps and enemies to find food for his family

- Programming main character's behaviour
- Developed save system
- Maintenance and error resolution.
- Handling user interactions and interface animations.
- Developed AI behaviour
- •Integrated animations, sound effects, models and textures in the game

NOT SO BEE-ZY - PC VIDEO GAME FEBRUARY 2021 - JUNE 2021

I was the producer and programmer of a project developed with Unity about a lazy bee that instead of working decides to steal polem from her sisters, this stealth game is designed for a casual audience and full of irreverent humor.

- Programming main character's behaviour
- Developed save system
- Maintenance and error resolution.
- Handling user interactions and interface animations.
- Developed AI behaviour
- •Integrated animations, sound effects, models and textures in the game